Analyze Contributing Forces
Welcome back to our session on value creation.
We’re now moving into step four, which is analyzing contributing forces.
So, if I take measure existing conditions and analyze contributing forces,
then those are the two critical things to help me configure my goals.
Now, we’re going to come play this out more later on,
but for now let's zero in on this idea of analyzing contributing forces.
Now, recall from last time, we said that Y is a function of X.
And that we have our baseline condition.
Which in the example that we gave that base condition, right there, 8 o'clock in the morning.
That is when the newspaper came.
And we had a problem with the dog going out there and eating the newspaper.
So, we said that if we can get the newspaper delivered at six in the morning,
we move toward this rightful level of expectation. Six in the morning.
The dog wouldn't be there to eat the paper and therefore I can read it.
And have the opportunity, over here, move me from not having a job
to maybe closer toward having a job.
But remember, this is only one element we talk here.
The real world is Y is a function of X1 to Xn. There are many variables.
So, every opportunity is a function of many conditions,
for which there is the vital few and the trivial many, we talked about.
Now, I want to focus in on the vital few
and look at how we analyze those in a situation
such as the time of morning the newspaper is delivered.
To do that, I'm going to set up a simple little T-bar.
Here. And over here, I’ve got driving forces.
And over here, I've got restraining forces.
Now, this is kinda cool. For example, the dog.
This is a condition, by the way.
This is a force and that force is a condition.
What we’re looking at is the condition’s force.
How strong is that force of when the newspaper is delivered?
See. How strong is it? Well, I draw an arrow
to kinda correspond. The length of this arrow
corresponds to the strength of the force.
So, this is condition one. What time the newspaper is delivered.
Well, how motivated I am, in the morning, is another big driving force.
See, that's a bigger force maybe than the dog. You know, there's a lot of other forces.
Some big, some little itty-bitty forces. I want to think of all those forces
that tend to drive toward the realization of that opportunity.
Then, on the other hand, there are restraining forces.
There are forces that tend to keep me
from realizing that opportunity.
So now remember, an opportunity
is a set of conditions
favorable to an end.
Some of these conditions in here. I’m going to make a little matrix out of it.
Some of these conditions are drivers. Some are restraining forces.
Some are among the vital few. Some are among the trivial many.
Well what I want to analyze. I only want to analyze the driving and restraining forces
that are the vital few. Again, recognize some of these are here,
and some of these conditions are there.
Some conditions drive, some conditions restrain.
I want to ignore the trivial many. I don’t even want to look at those.
See, so by going in, finding the vital few,
defining the vital few driving and restraining conditions,
for the opportunity. I do that right up here. Scaling them, see.
I gotta scale them. Some are big, some are small.
What I'm looking at is like two people pushing on a door. This is a door.
Person on one side, person on the other, two forces.
This person pushes this way, door wants to swing that way.
But, if this person’s stronger, the doors going to swing that way.
So, what we’re analyzing, is which way are the forces pushing me?
Are they pushing this opportunity, right here,
to a positive direction?
Or is it pushing it over here in a negative direction.
I gotta analyze those forces to determine that. Then, very simply.
I have to pick, which of these forces I'm going to go take action on.
To change that situation.
To change it from moving in a negative direction.
In other words, of a lessening opportunity, to where the opportunity is increasing.
What am I going to do? I gotta go pick those forces, select them.
So, those are going to be my top hitters.
Those are going to be the knobs I go turn to make things get better.
Those are the knobs I’m going to go turn to make the quality improve.
To make the value bucket start to fill.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.